so what you're saying is before I report
I should disclose and then report the
same day
sorry so it's one day sure if you want
to time it so that you you get your own
CBE the CV gets public then you publish
your own POC and that's what it is
before everybody else yeah I mean yeah I
guess that's a public exploit it's gonna
be a gonna be a busy couple days
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
I just saw you get like prepped you you
like the countdown started you backed up
you like hyped yourself up it's got a
little stress get a little get a little
you know dude I'm getting myself ready
for this one because this is going to be
this is gonna be a feisty one today I'm
gonna have to bring the Feist to the
show oh boy all right because we are
representing we got in in the left
corner we have Justin Gardner
representing the hackers
representing the hackers and the program
managers yeah yeah I play devil's
advocate here yeah yeah no um it should
be a fun one man I'm excited and uh yeah
I'm gonna you know
we're pretty tight I I you know and and
so I just it's gonna feel good to like
just kind of rip you a new one in this
debate I think you know okay you know so
we'll start looking through this Dock
and there was a lot of very feisely
written points and I had some very
feisty written answers in my head so
that's great in true Joel fashion uh
you've got the feisely written stuff in
your head that's good
um all right so let's take let's take a
little Breath Take a little breather
calm down we got a News segment to hit
before we get into the meat
um all right so first up on the news
well first of all we're kind of a little
bit a little bit light on news this week
um I don't know if that's just because
everyone like dumped all their stuff at
oh Defcon yeah I was gonna I actually
haven't even asked you about Defcon how
is Defcon yeah I mean Defcon was pretty
good I got covered so oh no the last
good side of it but uh yeah other than
that it was good it was fun it's great
to see everybody good to hang out with
people who sometimes I don't even get to
see people like you know once a year so
yeah it's it's always a nice time do
go to Defcon itself or just h1702 I did
I didn't even step foot in the
convention center I didn't buy a badge
but like honestly it doesn't seem like I
miss out on much given what the badges
were this year but uh yeah no I'm my
personal opinion is that uh most of the
time the talks are all uploaded
um except for I think a couple of The
Villages sometimes don't do it there's
like a whole thing with that but um for
the most part pretty much every single
talk is uploaded on YouTube so if
there's stuff that I didn't get to see
I can just go see it oftentimes the
really good talks I could I'll just hear
what they are and I'll go look them up
um yeah and like I said that all the
people that I I that I tend to see I end
up seeing outside of Defcon
um I really like going to Defcon to see
the talks but like one of the
disadvantages that you can't see
everything so yeah you know I figured
I'd save my money enjoy Vegas a little
bit a little more chill a little bit
less money and then enjoy Vegas sure
save my money bye yeah tables or
whatever
gamble at all yeah yeah
all right we're not sure from the tone
of that yeah I say we're not going to go
down that path all right I yeah I didn't
walk away a Mega millionaire I'll didn't
walk away all right well that's that's
that's part of the experience I suppose
yeah and and about the talks you know
yeah I kind of agree I think there's
something cool about being able to go in
person especially if it's your friends
you know and support them and and um you
know ask questions afterwards if you
have questions but yeah most of the time
on those talks you're going to want to
rewind and like take notes and like you
know dive a little bit deeper so it's
nice that they put them up on on you
know YouTube a little bit later yeah
yeah actually they're already up on on
the Defcon YouTube so yeah yeah they are
yeah definitely been a couple weeks so
if you want to go check out those talks
they're all available yeah yeah it's
been it's been a long couple weeks man
you know I I realized we haven't
actually had uh Justin and Joel episode
since then so yeah that's yeah first you
had covet then I had covered yeah I got
a covet on a cruise that was that was
rough
um let's see here all right well let's
let's hit the news then
um first item up on the list all I'll
talk about was uh was rezzo uh a loyal a
loyal follower of the podcast bless his
heart
um released something really cool called
uh prompt injection primer for engineers
and essentially it's a uh it's a
document outlining what kind of things
you need to be worried about as an
engineer from uh with regards to prom
prompt injection and
um yeah I know we have a lot of
Engineers listening to this to this pod
so I wanted to shout it out and if any
of you are working with
um AI related uh tools and are are kind
of a little bit worried about what
prompt injection may as it is an
unresolved bug we still don't have a
solution to prompt injection that's
perfect you know it's not like just
escaping our you know uh double quotes
and single quotes in SQL and stuff like
that it's it's unsolved problem
um I think Joseph does a good job here
of breaking down what exactly the the
attack Vector is he's got a little flow
chart on whether you need to be worried
about it or not so I think this could
make it a lot easier for people to
understand what kind of impact this bug
could have
yeah it's super interesting um I saw
that he had posted on Twitter and it
seems like a great resource to just sort
of like put some stuff out in in this
space of security uh it's such a new
technology and there's so many things
that we haven't really figured out like
you said it's it's like an unresolved
problem so I think it's great to have
some awesome Minds like rezo and I think
yourself as well right um you know so I
may have seen it you know before it was
released you know yeah so it's good to
have these these types of Minds uh
already working on the problem already
putting out resources out there helping
companies get secure before they even
know it so yeah yeah for sure
um so definitely check that out if
you're if you're working with AI stuff
at all pass it around to anybody who is
working with AI because we all kind of
saw what happened with web3 when
everyone went crazy boom with web3 stuff
you know everyone was developing it was
happening so fast loans were flying all
over the place money was flying out of
wallets left and right and so luckily AI
is not directly linked to currency like
like uh like web3 was but um not yet
yeah right exactly not not yet uh so we
hopefully we won't have quite as severe
of a Fallout but
um definitely something to check out if
you're working with it yeah um
did you see this thing from portswiger
research drops something so they dropped
a um I guess Chrome now supports the on
scroll end sort of event handler
um so this is a great way to get past
those pesky laughs for I don't know
hopefully a month or two uh until they
update their word list or whatever but
um it works on any element so in in the
the little tweet that we'll Link in the
description they have it working on the
xss element right the little fake xss
element and if you combine this with the
auto scroll to a specific element
feature that they have in in Chrome if
you put like the ID in the hashtag in
the hash fragment uh up at the URL then
you can just pop it without any
interaction nice nice that's awesome
yeah this is one of those accounts uh
you mentioned this way early in the Pod
and I followed suit right after you did
but I have tweet notifications turn off
reports Twitter research because it's
just one of those accounts that is
constantly pumping out really
like immediately useful information just
like this which is you know a screenshot
and a link to their their post about
this specific vector and how you can use
it you know it doesn't get much better
than that so yeah yeah this is a super
super interesting especially if xsses
are your bread and butter on scrollland
there you go
yeah so excess that's that's that for
xss the next thing that I wanted to talk
about was uh this talk that Gunner
Andrews AKA golden infosec did at Recon
Village I saw this pop up on YouTube and
I know that he's been working what the
heck my Google home just started
freaking out in front of me stop
unplugged
um maybe Gunner Andrews does it activate
my Gunner what did you do oh no did you
activate my Google home no absolutely
yeah no I know he does some crazy Recon
stuff with regards to
um specifically with regards to
serverless architecture so I was really
thrilled to see that Recon Village put
up a talk by him
um just like Joe was talking about in
the beginning of the episode you know
you don't necessarily have to be at
Defcon to get all this wonderful
information that they released and uh I
watched through this talk and it's super
awesome and not not only does he come in
he's not like a serverless fanboy either
like he comes in and he says like hey
this is the these are the pros and cons
of serverless this this is when you
should use serverless this is when you
should just use a server you know
um and and so he does a really good job
of outlining what kind of tasks uh work
best uh in in serverless architecture
um and how to use that to power your bug
bounty hunting and your recon
um so definitely a hard recommend on
that one yeah I'm gonna I've got that on
my list so I'm gonna have to watch it
after we we finish recording yeah it's
got I want to say how long is it 40
minutes yeah I put it on I put it on 2X
and I was still getting the full the
full value out of it
um so definitely definitely worth a
listen awesome
all right before we hop in to the main
content real quick
Jason Haddix former guest of the show
um Jay Haddix Jason addicts whatever you
want you know him by uh he is doing a
course it's the bug Hunters methodology
live training course and he has very
generously given us a
invite code to give away so one of our
listeners uh will be randomly selected
to get a free access to his live bug
Hunters methodology 550 value yeah I
mean huge values so first of all major
shout out to to Jason thank you we uh we
can't appreciate it enough we're hoping
that uh whichever view ends up winning
this uh will get the most value out of
it as possible give us your notes give
us your notes yeah it's funny actually
funny story so I I had talked to Jason
about this and Jason's like yeah you
know I can I could probably give you a
code to give away on the Pod you know
something like that and so he messages
me the the link and then he's like oh I
should probably just message Joel the
link as well so he just like drops the
discount code in Joel's DMS right it's
just like oh heck yeah like I can't wait
to go to this course like this is gonna
be awesome and and I'm like no Joel
that's that's for that's for the
listeners okay I saw it I was like oh
I'm I'm gonna have to claim that later
and then yeah like a couple hours later
I was talking about it with Justin and
he was like oh no we're gonna give that
away I was like okay it looks like it's
the same code and then like within a few
minutes I get a message from Jason he's
like by the way that's that's the
giveaway of the podcast
you could see the disappointment in
Joel's eyes like yeah so so definitely
uh you're going to want to enter to win
this uh we have a very easy way to entry
just go to ctbb.show slash giveaway and
that's you'll be taken somewhere
probably Google form haven't really
figured it out yet but somewhere on the
new website potentially yeah on our new
website yeah so ctbb.show slash giveaway
and that's how you can enter to win a
free entry to Jason haddix's Bug Hunter
methodology course
yeah and I'm looking through this this
chorus man and I was reading through the
description and it says explicitly uh so
I think this matches well with the with
the critical thinking audience unlike
other courses uh tbhm live is not an A
to Z or beginners oriented course and
I'm looking through the the syllabus and
this is a lot of content that he's gonna
try to cover in two days so I imagine
he'll be moving pretty quickly
um looks like a very a very interesting
course so definitely check that out
um and like I sort of vaguely mentioned
just a second ago and totally forgot to
announce at the beginning we have
launched a new website for critical
thinking it is live
um it will have it's going to be a
little bit better organized than our our
past website so we've got each episodes
popping up we've got the video we've got
the audio whichever your preferred
medium is we've also got transcripts
which is something a lot of you guys
have been asking for for a long time
um those will be attached to each
podcast release I'm not sure that it'll
be it'll be on like the instant that the
episode drops but hopefully within the
first couple hours of an episode
dropping we should have the transcript
up there
um and ready for you guys to consume so
uh there's also a contact form on the
website that you can get in touch with
us via so shoot any questions or
concerns about that over there
awesome all right should we uh should we
kick off the main
the main the main show I don't even know
the main the main attraction let's see
all right Richie we're gonna need you to
Richie's our editor Richie put in like
some sort of you know or something like
that here some epic start foreign
[Applause]
okay I do currently work at a tech
company I'm not even gonna name them
we're just going to keep it completely
out of this
um I do manage Bugatti programs there
however everything that we're gonna say
today has nothing to do with my employer
has nothing to do with my job it has
nothing to do with my day-to-day
um if anything
remotely like sensitive or anything
we're gonna cut it out so
um yeah I just want to clarify that like
this is based on my experience as a
program manager and a bug Bounty Hunter
this is not reflective of my employer or
my current work or anything like that
okay nice fully just fully red tape out
of the way yeah there you go very nice
and you've had
um you know you've managed other
programs in the past before too yeah
yeah and I'm happy to say like I you
know before my current role I was at
Uber I managed yeah I helped well I
didn't manage it but I helped manage it
uh alongside the main manager
um so yeah I definitely have had my
fingers in a lot of different programs
from the program side for a couple many
many years now so all right all right
disclaimer is all over
boxing boxing gloves are on Joel boxing
gloves off on let's go wait off what the
heck's gonna like knuckle to the face
um boxing gloves on so I'm going into my
my state I'm going into my hacker hacker
representation State dude
what is up with the what is up with the
zero day policy man like if your scope
is vulnerable and it's in scope why am I
not getting paid for this awesome zero
day that I found okay so like for the
record I think a lot of things we will
probably like semi agree on
some of this should really be like sort
of to the other program managers if your
program isn't experienced to this you
know this is sort of my take that I
think I need you to definitely Advocate
a little bit though okay so like I know
you're a hacker and I know you're a good
program manager right and so I realize
you know we may agree on some things but
also I want to hear the other side as
well you know yeah so so I'll tell you
sort of both aspects from it so yeah why
why shouldn't you get paid I mean
there's there's a couple reasons I think
the main reason is that there's nothing
that can be done from the company side
to fix this and I think we've discussed
this a little bit when we talk with
shubs
about
sort of how to navigate that kind of
communication when you're reporting a
zero day vulnerability especially if
it's something that you've found uh to a
company and whether or not they should
be paying it and a lot of it boils down
to what is the company supposed to do
because for one it's nothing that their
Engineers cause it's nothing that they
accidentally added or who was there like
this is just an artifact of the fact
that they use a piece of software and
that other company made a mistake
okay their Engineers did do something
here because they put it they put a
domain you know presumably they put a
domain pointing to this asset you know I
don't know if it's a cloud asset you
know if it's a cloud asset then they
just pointed their domain at it but you
guys made the decision just like you
would use you know to use open source
software to run work with this provider
and that has inherently put your users
at risk sure yeah and so that's where I
like I'll start to agree with you is
that like there are certainly systemic
steps that you can take from a company
side to help stop these things and that
generally involves like
doing audits ahead of time with the
company discussing what their current
security team and current security
practices look like how do they store
data what are their password policies
what is their internal security policy
like there's a lot of things that you
can do as sort of checks and balances to
try and make sure that the company
you're about to work with and whose
software about you're about to use will
not compromise you but at the end of the
day you like you didn't write the code
you're you probably don't even have
access to the source code and so
depending on what it is like there might
not be much you can do and yes they they
the engineers probably did create a DNS
don't give me that [__] Joel
but they didn't do anything wrong from a
security from a secure development
standpoint okay there's nothing that the
engineer could have done differently
that would have stopped them from being
vulnerable it was completely out outside
of their control okay okay that's sort
of true that that is true and I I see
that point but also
heck that and and and I need the Bounty
right yeah right now now yeah sure so so
like again I agree with you and I think
this is sort of where like from a
program management perspective where I
draw the line is basically
is there impact yes or no pay for impact
right yeah like yeah it doesn't
necessarily matter if it's your fault it
matters whether or not
something can happen because of that
vulnerability right yeah and so at the
end of the day like you should be taking
responsibility for the impact to your
business to your users to your customers
whatever it is that like if you're using
a piece of software that makes you
vulnerable you should pay for that to
some extent now I think it's fair to not
pay a full Bounty because there's a
limited amount of things that you can do
I also think that
there needs to be some sort of like
you know how do I think conversation
yeah okay okay sure but like how do I
fix this right like okay you're
reporting a zero day to me can I set up
firewall rule up can I yeah I mean laugh
like what do I do to fix it what do you
want me the company who uses this piece
of software to do because
if it if the other company doesn't even
know about it the only thing that we can
do is say hey by the way there's a volt
in your software you need to fix this
okay so I I'm I'm uh I got the little
you know hyperbolized hacker out of my
system a little bit there and the Raging
but I I'm gonna try to approach this
from uh from an intellectual perspective
as a as a hacker here so my answer to
that would be that
um you know sure you don't you guys
don't have access to the source the
vulnerable source code that's running on
the Target right assuming it's closed
Source uh you know project or whatever
um and so how do you remediate that
situation totally fair question I I
think and I whenever I report these I
always try to include some sort of
remediation step may it be
um you know changing some configuration
in the actual third-party app that you
know you can find in the settings but at
the end of the day you can just stick a
WAFF in front of it or you can stay I
mean how hard is it to like spin up an
nginx reverse proxy right and and like
just block off a specific endpoint
significantly easier said than done are
you serious yes because okay here's the
thing in a perfect Universe where every
company is just like five Engineers with
an AWS box yeah that works you could
just like spit up a service and be done
with it but in most modern tech
companies there's so much more process
and procedure and like trying to fit
into the existing Technologies and they
might not even use nginx like there's so
many other layers that don't just make
it that easy where yes that would be a
super easy solution if it worked but
it's completely dependent on
implementation and use case okay but
like almost every organization is using
some sort of reverse proxy right like
you know whether it be uh you know
Apache nginx trafic or however you
pronounce that thing yeah or have a
laugh right like you know and so just I
mean
I don't know maybe this is my lack of
Enterprise experience coming into play
but it but if I were on a security team
and I got a report of this and I you
know there's an rce on this box you know
that you can only access to a certain
point
I I would want to be you know spinning
up a you know AWS you know reverse proxy
what do they I forget what they're
called uh but I mean like the thing is
that like yeah
there's a few things that you can that
you can do right if it's not something
but it's business critical ipret it take
it offline yeah put it behind the
firewall put it behind VPN yeah let's
change the configuration there's usually
like a handful of things that you can
sort of generically do that will
probably help if it's an actual zero day
you know there's like very few things
that the company can do outside of like
preventative measures around like
preventing questions right yeah so
there's not much you can fix
um I I see that you also mentioned one
days in here honestly my opinion is that
if it's a one day like that's fair game
if there's an export out there publicly
especially and
you have the software and it's publicly
exposed that is fair game so what you're
saying is before I report I should
disclose and then report the same day
sure if you want to dive in so that you
you get your own CBE the CV gets public
then you publish your own POC and that's
what it is before everybody else yeah I
mean yeah I guess that's a public
exploit it's gonna be a gonna be a busy
couple days in that scenario yeah
um no okay yeah that makes it and I I do
agree if it's got a public CV you know
then
you know even if you're aware of it I
always add that
um
having to do less asset
you know enumeration or checking of your
assets to say like hey yeah this is this
bug is vulnerable to this I think that
adds value
um and so there's there's definitely
some other areas where the bug bounty
hunters add value with their reports and
also it's an easier sell to the people
that need to fix it say okay yeah sure
that somebody posted this paper that
affects our bloody blah but it's a
different story when you can say
actually a hacker shelled this box this
morning and was in here and could have
deleted the whole system you know I feel
like that's an easier to sell to your
bureaucratic organization or whatever
yeah and I I think like generally each
of these topics probably has some sort
of useful takeaway from it from a
program perspective so like for this
case like having better
management and knowledge of your assets
and what software is running on each
asset that's probably a decent takeaway
if you're getting affected by zero day
reports and one day reports a lot like
that should tell you that from our
security program perspective you need to
be identifying what software is running
on your boxes better excuse me in like a
more efficient way and being able to
update that stuff in a more efficient
way and
yeah hand in hand with that also knowing
what vulnerabilities are in the pipeline
that are affecting your software so that
you can fix it ASAP yeah now that
totally makes sense Mariah's texting me
something let me just let me just send
her this okay all right yeah and and I
think I think um
yeah I think that that piece about patch
management is very important you know
and and oftentimes people
I guess maybe I shouldn't say oftentimes
but I've seen several times when people
have started bug bounding programs and
they don't have a solid patch management
platform out and I just can think of
this one time with my automation where
like every week I was getting this ping
this is vulnerable this is Honorable
this is vulnerable this is one of them
they didn't patch the cve this critical
cve that leaked AWS creds right yeah for
over a year and I'm like what are you
doing
um so anyway so all right you know now I
gotta get what are you doing uh we'll
get to that shortly because okay we'll
we'll get to that don't I know that's in
there that's enough that's not the next
question the next question is
um
okay so let's talk a little bit about
disclosure okay
um
I have done some research I've found a
vulnerability I reported to you because
I want to give you a heads up
uh but I also want to be able to
disclose this but I would also like to
be paid for my research
why why not why like you know a lot of
programs add do not disclose policies
what's up with that homeboy yeah okay so
I mean the reality is that a lot of this
boils down to the fact that a lot of
programs have a legal and calm steam
yeah or both illegal teams and a comps
team and
oftentimes security vulnerabilities are
viewed positively by the security
Community negatively by everybody else
um and so if you think about it it's
like yeah that's interesting the company
doesn't really want to brag that they
had a security vulnerability right the
incentive there is good for the security
team to be like look our bug Bounty
program's working great terrible from a
comms and publicity perspective around
like oh customer data could have been at
risk or whatever right like I think that
is always the challenge and some
companies are very good about owning
security and being like we don't give a
[__] we're going to be public about
everything and like if we have a
security vulnerability that's great we
don't care we'd rather be public about
it and it doesn't really matter
um I think a lot of companies get really
scared about that and rightfully so
because there's been plenty of outrage
for various tech companies Uber for
example around security vulnerabilities
and how it was handled and how it was
announced or not announced and all that
kind of stuff can take the stock price
and all that sort of thing right and so
like I think that is a real risk there
now the the other side is like okay I
want to get paid great report it to the
bug Bounty program I want to disclose it
well that's up to the program
um I I see a lot of researchers who will
report stuff and they get frustrated
when they aren't allowed to disclose or
they you know disclose anyways or or
whatever like
here's the reality of it when you submit
a bug through a bug Bounty program you
agree to the bug body program terms and
policy
that states that you can't disclose
stuff without the permission of the
program if you disclose stuff without
the permission of the program you are
violating the program terms which number
number one often excludes you from Safe
Harbor Productions and number two sets
you up for a platform ban or at least
some sort of a suspension or or
repercussion right yeah and so
that's not to say that you can't report
stuff without being able to disclose it
you can always like email security at
and you know reach out to them directly
not going through the bug body program
you're not agreeing to their program
terms if you're not going through the
through the bug banning program I wonder
I wonder if you could submit directly to
the bug Bounty program but still but
like explicitly state in the report that
I decline the terms and agreements to
this uh and say like I I you know I
intend to disclose this bug but I'm also
giving you a heads up
I don't know yeah I mean maybe I think
that would be a little more nuanced
because there's probably some stuff in
the hacker one in terms of service that
says right like you know whatever but
it's definitely a way to set you up for
platform problems for sure yeah like
here's I just wouldn't recommend it and
like yeah the other aspect of it is if
you really want to want to disclose
something and the company really doesn't
you're gonna set yourself up for a rocky
relationship with that company in that
program
every day after that because
if you decide to go ahead and disclose
and they don't want to do it they are
really not going to want to work with
you in the future right so if you find
something like
you know some some other like really bad
phone and you want to report it to them
or you want to like you know get a
bounty or something how is that company
supposed to feel when they've got this
researcher who's like been super
aggressive with them in the past about
disclosures and now coming in them with
another vulnerability yeah like yeah
they're gonna fix it yeah probably it
doesn't feel safe gonna want to like you
know it it really sets a bad precedent I
think for that type of for the type of
relationship that you want to have with
the program which is like an amicable
working relationship where you can
professionally yeah you can secure
things together and both be like happy
and positive about it not be like I want
to disclose this you can't disclose it
or I'm mad about that like right you
know like at the end of the day that's
part of what that's part of the bargain
right part of the bargain is that you
get paid so
right like that feels a little bit dirty
if you say like if you say it like that
because you said that's part of the
bargain and it is part of the bargain
and you're totally right in representing
it that way but essentially what you
just said is we're paying you to keep
your mouth shut which is like really
sketchy and not the way that I I I
really want to see bug bounties yeah and
I mean like I don't want to get too
reductive here because I think that you
could frame
a lot of things that way but especially
with any private program you could
phrase it that way and then like you're
oh you don't have a public program so
like uh why you know I don't know or
like oh things are out of scope like if
it's out of scope then like you know
you're basically just like telling me
not to look at something that's
vulnerable or not like I think there's a
lot of reductive ways that you could
take that same kind of difference yeah
and while I while I see it I think that
it's a little more nuanced than that
like bug Bounty programs are not just
designed to pay a researcher they're
designed to set a neutral environment in
place so that researchers can
communicate things safely with the
program and the program can communicate
things safely with the researcher fix it
not worry about like the researcher
leaking their payload or telling other
people about it and all this other kind
of stuff and in return the researcher
gets paid for that you know for not
telling other people about
right that's kind of where I was
thinking you know with this is like the
incentive
the keeping your mouth shut piece is a
little bit more of a of a
um
other addendum to the whole situation
the the motivating factor for a bug
Bounty program is these uh you know
researchers have done high quality
security research and deserve to be
rewarded for that and to be to be
compensated for that and so
um I think that's the primary you know
Services exchange right yeah I mean yes
yes however part of high quality
security research in my opinion involves
how the delivery is handled and so you
can't just do high quality research and
then start making demands about what you
should be paid and how it should be
handled that's a good point passage
should be fixed and all this kind of
stuff that's right like again you're
participating in the bug Bounty program
if you want to kind of stuff that's a
security ad and you want to strong arm
the program you can by all means go
ahead and try that and they may or may
not respond but they also may or may not
respond in a very nice way sure I'm I'm
uh you know to all you hackers out there
I'm trying he's just doing good you know
like like I I've tried to give them a
piece of our mind here but no these
these are very reasonable answers you're
you're you're coming across with Joel so
um I kind of put put you on the spot
this episode and I will continue to put
you on the spot that's fine listen these
are a lot of things that I used to feel
as a hacker myself I still understand
where a lot of hackers are coming from
with these things but having worked on
the other side it the answers and the
reasons behind stuff are so much more
nuanced I think it's important that
people understand it yeah yeah me too
um with that being said let's talk about
hideous piece of bug bounties which is
dupes and particularly internal dupes
what the heck dude like what so okay
hold on I am gonna rant a little bit
about this okay so if you've got an
internal dupe and
it you have not you know resolved this
thing right and it's within a longer
time frame than one would expect you
know a couple months for you know maybe
even a high or medium or like a couple
weeks for for a crit
like okay that that seems like something
that you need to still pay the
researcher for because you're sitting on
that bug and like I I have put in high
quality this I'm sorry you can tell it's
a little bit a little bit fresh okay
um but you know I put in this high
quality research you've known about this
issue for a while my time just went down
the drain and is still violated and and
it's you know are sort of agreement that
we have in place of I provide you with
high quality security research and you
pay me for that and when no other hacker
had reported it this is an internal dupe
either discovered from code review or
maybe like an internal pen test or
something like that just feels like crap
and how can we get accountability for
that as as a hacker how can we
understand when truly this is an
internal dupe or whether you know we're
getting screwed out of our bounty
yeah so there's a lot of nuance and
angles so this I think what I'll start
with is that
I'll address that last part first which
is how can I be sure that this really is
an internal dupe yeah main thing I would
say is where is the incentive for the
program to lie to you
in the long term yeah money but I'm I'm
yeah those of you probably get together
listening to a podcast I'm listening
rubbing my fingers together I'm taking a
sip of water yes now yes money however
reputation right and I think reputation
from the program perspective whether or
not programs actually view it this way
but the reality is that your reputation
is significantly
easier to damage than it is to like
spend money right and so like you're
gonna damage your reputation
significantly more
with the hackers Yeah by like you know
either lie like if you lie to a to a
hacker and say oh this is an internal
dude but it's not instead of just paying
for something the damage your reputation
if that comes out or whatever is so much
worse than whatever you paid for that
Bounty yeah no one's ever gonna touch
that program with a 10-foot pole exactly
right and so like the the incentive for
a program to lie like that is just like
you know you have to think about it like
why would somebody do that and it's not
that it doesn't happen but I think that
there's not a great incentive to start
with for like why would that like what
is the reason for like some random
employee who's running this program to
like come sign on and be like um I don't
want to pay for this I'm going to tell
them because it's not like it's their
money anyway right like it's not like
it's the the employees money like it's
not coming out of their salary right you
know
I mean we could get into that in the
next it wasn't in the budget part but
there would be no kpis associated with
how much money this bug Bounty program
is is paying or isn't paying with there
I prop budgets are very con very
complicated
budgets are very complicated
buckets are very very complicated things
uh the way that budgets at companies
especially the larger the company uh the
more confusing and weird it gets around
who gets what money for what thing
how does that process get approved uh
how do you get more money uh how do you
get more money next year like there's a
lot of different aspects to budgets and
that kind of stuff and you have to
remember that bug Bounty at the end of
the day when they make a payment that
comes out of a budget that has been set
aside probably at the beginning of the
year for bug bounty and
that pool is all they have to work with
and so if they run out of money that's a
problem and if they have too much money
that's also a problem so we're kind of
jumping ahead a little bit we are
jumping here but so I wanted to try to
Corner you with that but somehow you've
eased your way out of it that that's uh
okay let's just say take it back for a
second so like the main thing is that I
personally don't think that many
programs really have much to gain by
lying to a hacker especially like it's a
bug value program like what what is your
the point if you're lying to the main
like thing that matters to you right
like you might as well just not have a
program that's my personal take I don't
know if that's how most programs are I
sure hope that they don't lie to the
attackers but you never know
um yeah okay separate from that
is
how how do you not get your time wasted
right
I think that is really really difficult
well I forgot I asked that question
Joel's got like a like okay all right I
see it you're on it today yeah I think
like
so
this risk is always there right like if
you take internal dupe if you just take
the word internal out of it and leave
dupe like that's always been a risk
right the risk has always been there
that a researcher could have reported it
and you find it tomorrow and
you do and your time is wasted maybe you
spent two weeks and you reported it you
said I'll report it tomorrow
and you get duped okay that risk is
always there
the fact that it's found by a not a
security researcher but maybe a security
engineer instead
is very little change in that situation
now
I think that a lot of programs could do
a better job at documenting that and
integrating it into their program and
what do I mean by that I mean
if you have a security vulnerability on
a public-facing endpoint you could
create a ticket on your bug Manning
program an internal like you know close
it is informative or whatever like I
don't there are ways to handle that but
or import it and
if you need to reference it from like a
public report that later comes in you
have an actual report ID that you can
refer with a time stamp and that sort of
thing yeah yeah the other thing I think
that you can do that's probably honestly
easier is just be transparent and this I
think goes a long way in a lot of
different areas but I'll talk about it
right now which is that you should be
defaulting to transparency with the
researcher number one oftentimes they're
Bound by an NDA number two they're Bound
by your program terms number three
they're Bound by privacy policy on
hacker one like there are a lot of
aspects where you can have some level of
comfort with the researcher and just be
transparent with them about what's going
on and that applies in a lot of
different aspects for this aspect that
applies in that if there's an internal
dupe take a screenshot of the internal
ticket and send it to them you don't
have to include all the information you
you could react stuff but just like show
them that it's real like if that's what
like show them that it's a thing and
that they missed it by three weeks or
whatever and I also think to that point
right as you mentioned like what happens
if it's open for a year or whatever
right
there should be uh programs should be
taking accountability for that okay like
I don't think it's acceptable if you
have a high or a critical especially
severity vulnerability
that is open for a long period of time
that means your security team is not
doing their job they should be getting
this fixed they should this should be a
priority for them it should be a
priority for the engineers I understand
that there's lots of work culture and
all sorts of other things that could
play into that relationship between
security and Engineering it does not
matter if you're going to have a bug
Bounty program that means you have to
take security seriously you preach to
fix your stuff in a reasonable period of
time or you have to explain that to your
researchers and say sorry
I know this has been open for a year and
but it's still not fixed yet and then
you have to be willing to to own that
and and and answer as to why not right
and I I think that's just a reality that
a lot of programs like don't want to
accept is that like sometimes stuff that
should be high priority isn't
prioritized and
you know that that sucks yeah so yeah I
I I I agree with you and I'll also take
like a program at like Advocate side
here which is that like
internal dupes are real they do happen
however programs can be a lot better
about being transparent they can provide
more information about the dupe itself
show that it's you know open that it's
being worked on whatever and if stuff is
open for too long you have to take
security seriously and realize that a
real attacker would go and exploit that
if you had that open for a year
and yeah there's no excuse for it to not
be fixed
I I hope that the work of the Lord is
being done here
it's um that was fire dude not good good
[__] okay
um I was supposed to disagree with you
and debate that at all but to be honest
it was pretty on fleek and I really
appreciated the the point you know about
them taking responsibility for and I
think that's a little bit what we want
with the transparency right like if we
can get a ticket showing hey uh you
missed it by two days then that's like
well drat you know like I still hate
that for me but uh you know it's not the
end of the world right but if I see a
ticket that says that this you know
problem has been around for six months
or something then I'm gonna be I'm gonna
be a little bit a little bit salty right
and so when when they don't when they
say hey sorry internal dupe you know
then that that makes me feel a little
bit like they're trying to hide
something and that this bug's been
around for a while and this program is
just a you know pilot
yeah and like goodness you just have to
remember that like every company is
different the amount of resources that
they have both on the engineering side
and the security side are different per
company and so
there's this thing called slas I'm not
going to explain it I feel like you can
look up what an SLA is a service level
agreement okay it basically just means
you have this much time to fix this
thing or deal with this thing right
that's like time to First Response all
that kind of stuff those are slas okay
every company has different slas for
tickets and especially security tickets
some don't even have slas clearly
defined for security tickets and so if
something's been open for six months
that could be the normal for the company
okay and if that's the normal there's
really not much to do as a researcher
about that no it's not good but you
can't be like ah fix this faster because
do you own that company are you a C
Level on there that's true you know the
security one the security team only has
so much leverage and two like you're
asking for large structural changes to
how stuff gets done and yeah it would be
correct and better and awesome to see it
get fixed faster but if that's not how
they prioritize security and Engineering
then that's not how they prioritize
security and Engineering that's yeah it
is what it is and I feel like some of
this is also a little bit on the
platforms because like you whenever you
as a platform when you bring somebody on
for a bug bounding program you have two
customers you have the the company and
you have the hacker right and if you're
going to bring on a a client right a
customer a a company and then they're
going to provide really poor service to
your other client that's not good so I I
think there needs to be some auditing in
place and I'm sure there is at some
levels in some organizations but I think
there really needs to be some sort of
standard SLA Assurance or something like
that where hacker one or bug crowd or
Integrity says uh yes uh bugs
even if they don't always hit it they
should be shooting for bugs to be fixed
in a certain amount of time right and
you sort of see that on the program
policies but um those numbers are very
very uh
you know I can't come up with the word
and the Japanese word just keeps on
coming into my head but they're very
like not specific and not
stuck to you know and so I I would like
to see a little bit more adherence
around that because that's very
important to the hackers yeah I'd say
like around around that it's very
difficult because
um it fluctuates too yeah I mean the
reality is that
hacker one is a vendor for a company
right from a company perspective hacker
one is a vendor you're paying hacker one
for their product.com or you know
whatever generic but or bug Crowder
we're just gonna use hacker one in place
here yeah
you're paying to use that platform and
in return you get access to the Inbox
and maybe you get access to triage
Services okay and the reality is that
they
you're not paying them for advice on how
to run your security program okay that
that's a problem though I think if that
if that's the if that is the case is
that truly the case
I mean there that's not what you're
paying for them you know you're not
paying them to tell you how to run your
your like they can give you advice but
it would be unsolicited right and so
that it like I think it would be better
if they were able to like meaningfully
give advice to companies but I think
it's not really their place to be doing
that because that's not what they're
being paid for and so not only is it an
overstep of their services but it's like
not really their cons like their concern
is to provide an excellent bug Bounty
platform that helps the company
communicate with researchers and receive
vulnerabilities and all that stuff yeah
but you can't provide an excellent bug
Bounty platform without it being a
two-way street right so if you're not
ensuring that the program is providing a
quality experience to the hackers then
you can't you then the platform is going
down sure right but again what is hacker
one gonna do say like oh in order to
sign this contract you have to provide
us that uh you know you you're gonna
adjust your security slas and do all the
like these things would be blockers
they would just lose business right
that's true and it's a company you know
yeah yeah the company will be like okay
we're just gonna go to bug crowd who
doesn't require that yeah or like yeah
whatever right like the reality is that
I think that would be too much of a
blocker when the goal is to just get
companies to adopt security more by
having a bug running program and having
a way to receive vulnerability reports
and it to make it a requirement that
they have to like Vamp it up and buff
their whole security program in order to
receive reports that's really difficult
that's a really hard sell yeah I don't
know man I I would like to see that sell
and maybe maybe this is a maybe
something that hacker one or bug crowd
or Integrity could could run with and
say like
these are hacker one
vetted programs or something like that
where you know and they have some sort
of extra symbol you know sort of like
they have for some of the other uh
things that I'm not even sure I can
mention exist in hacker one
um
you know I actually had a discussion
with them not related to work uh from
like a hacker side yeah I was asked as a
hacker to go whoa whoa whoa Joel you're
not a hacker today here it is all right
continue but like one of the things that
that I suggested was like
if you have some knowledge about the
Tech stack that's being used
why not provide security recommendations
for that Tech stack right if you know
about stuff or you know about trends
like that's an easy win for your
customer to like give them extra value
for the for the product right and maybe
you later turn that into an extra paid
feature I don't know I don't care but
like I think that there are certainly
things that they could do there that's
not quite going as far as saying here's
what you should have for your slas and
all that kind of stuff because I think
that is
I mean that's a very that's a very
intense decision as well I I acknowledge
in in order to hit those slas you may
even have to bring on additional
developers right which is a you know
there's so many more in here at least
yeah decision you know and so there
there are is a lot of nuance to that and
I guess I can argue for the ideal from
the side as the hacker but
um
I just feel like a bug Bounty program is
a more mature security decision you know
and in a VDP everyone should have a VPP
you can be throwing vdps out left and
right but I think any program is a
little bit
it is a little bit more of a mature
um security program decision and by that
point you should have a grip on this yes
I totally agree I think hacker one would
uh
enthusiastically disagree with
uh just based on the fact that it's
their their whole business to create and
start more programs that's why that's
why we could say whatever the heck we
want on critical thinking
that's good all right um so all right I
have CVSs is the next topic
little bit of a loaded topic
um
what do you think skip it and move on to
budget or do we want to sure
I mean sure like it's my take here maybe
I'll give you no no no no no no no no
okay okay that's true all right no
you're right you're right you're right
I've been asking the questions this
whole time give me your take I don't
think cbss
is very useful
that's it like okay
it is a factor that you can consider I
don't think it should be the only Factor
you consider and I don't think it's a
perfect system I don't think any system
like this whether you want to be the ISS
whether you want to be cbss whether you
want to be
ABCD I don't please don't okay a flying
you know
like okay fill in the blank right like
all of these systems are trying to solve
a problem that is incredibly difficult
to solve which is that you're trying to
take a case-by-case scenario that is
truly impact dependent and generify it
into a set of factors that you can apply
globally and that just doesn't really
work
um I we've had some really interesting
discussions me and you uh with programs
about this and
like from a optimization perspective
every program wants this because it
makes payouts easier it makes payouts
more consistent it makes processing bugs
and handle lines everything it
streamlines everything yeah okay that's
great however you can't you can't do
that like like you can't just say like
oh if it checks these boxes then it is
this bounty or it is this bad because
some cases yes you can do that
many cases you cannot okay so okay so
lots of lots of uh lots to unpack there
lots of uh you know coming up with a
problem and not coming up with a
solution and and
um
I'm actually gonna take a little bit of
a controversial position here that I am
slightly
slightly truly believing
um which is that CBS s is like so the
programs that really stick to CVSs they
it works well you know like like if you
look at at
um uh Shopify and you look at
um uh PayPal and some of the other ones
that really stick to it Like Glue I
think that rarely are the and maybe it's
just because those programs have really
good bounties which is also another
another thing right those programs pay
very high bounties so you know you could
get your bug rated at a medium 6.8 and
still be walking out there with you know
well into the four figures you know
um Range uh
but yeah I I think I think there doesn't
necessarily have to be a a a system that
makes it all all streamlined and stuff
but having some sort of Baseline for an
attacker to know and maybe this is just
a a piece in your policy where it's like
hey we really prioritize user data and
if you can get access to user data we
are very very interested in that or we
don't really care as much about user
data as we care about like you getting
access to our source code and if you can
get access to our source code you know
very bad
um that sort of direction is really
helpful for me in understanding the
threat model of a company yeah no I I
think that's a great Point like again I
I generally I air towards
trying to pay like I think programs
should be paying by impact like I think
that impact is really what matters it's
not about like
I got an xss that's great what can you
do with it like
Can you steal my data can you take over
my account can you only pop an alert
like what what is the actual impact of
this because if it's nothing then what
why am I paying you know a flat Bounty
for this or why am I paying what I paid
for the last exercise that could do an
account takeover on this xss which can
do nothing right right and I think
that type of information is really
important and what you said about like
if you really stick to cbss then it
works well I think it works well in the
sense that you have a consistent program
right so what that means is that one
your process is streamlined and two your
process is consistent so an xss is going
to grade the same is going to pay the
same all the time and if that's how you
want to handle your security program and
you say we've got this much money for
bug Bounty and we're just gonna you know
we're gonna pay 5K for every xss we're
going to pay 2K for every sub domain
takeover that's fine but you have to
like budget and account for that and
just be willing to regardless of the
impact you have to be willing to press
that button and pay the Bounty at the
amount right yeah and a lot of programs
I think don't look at it that way which
is fair like I I don't look at it that
way like we don't use CVSs and I don't
think cbss is a great solution because
of what I said like there's so much
Nuance in impact and so yeah what you
pointed out about like what does the
program care about this is something
that I see almost no programs do well
um
and like this is something that I think
should be addressed from a probably from
a platform perspective as well but there
needs to be a better way for programs to
explain to researchers what their
security threat model looks like
and what that means is
as a security team when you report a bug
to me how do I think about it what are
the things that I'm looking for how am I
creating the impact amen and so there's
not a great way to communicate that from
the program side to the hat to the
researcher side and especially for
programs that don't use CVSs
there's like basically zero guidance
right and so those are the programs
where you submit something and you're
like this is a crit for sure and then
they regrade it to a medium low and yeah
like you know you're like what just
happened right and oftentimes it may be
one of you know the early reports to
that program that you've you know you're
still trying to feel it out and that
takes literal like multiple reports to
start to feel out manually what does the
program care about how do they respond
to this type of stuff like do they care
about this do they not care about this
like understanding that stuff in a trial
and error method it really sucks from a
research in perspective and so I think
programs could definitely do a better
job
in saying we care about user data
specifically even maybe we care about
these user data fields now that that
second question right there you'll have
programs who will immediately say no to
that just because of legal and comms
like
they don't want to point out explicitly
Targets on specific stuff yeah right and
so like I get that but like that's fine
like you don't have to go that far just
say like we care about user data and we
would care if you can do you know X Y
and Z the other side that I see by the
way is like way too extreme in terms of
examples well where uh like I've seen a
crypto program for example where they
will say that we consider it a crit if
and then they have four bullet points
with very specific scenarios laid out of
like bit like detailed like oh you can
execute like X Y and Z through like a
specific I'm like right this function
ever returns a negative number then yeah
like we're screwed you know like I'm
just gonna go test this one specific use
case that I know your security team
already knows isn't vulnerable like you
know what I mean like that's not helpful
either so I think like being more
generic about like the things that you
care about not the specific scenarios
that you care about
um what definitely help and somehow
figuring out I don't have a great
solution for this either but somehow
figuring out some way to explain like
the way that your security team is
thinking about bugs when they come in
um is it on the main domain is does it
have access to cookies yeah can it talk
with the main domain uh are there ever
cookies scoped to this like some of
these things you can figure out as a
researcher some of these things the
program needs to provide dude like that
was great and I I think we need to start
a critical thinking bug Bounty program
consultancy based off of that this
conversation because there's a lot of
high quality stuff in there and I think
a lot of lessons you've learned as as
being on the program side and on the
hacker side in Extreme Ways on both
right managing some of the biggest bug
Bounty programs and also
um or contributing to some of the
biggest bug batting programs and also
hacking on you know the live hacking
events in the you know cream of the crop
scene there
um so that's that's really cool and and
I I think I think CVSs
um definitely has its flaws but for me
that consistency that you mentioned
that's kind of what I want to see
because if I can if I can see the
consistency if I know what the system is
then I can work within the system right
that's our whole that's our whole thing
as hackers is working within the system
and and making our goals get
accomplished right and we talked about
this a little bit with with NT but like
the ethical boundaries of sort of gaming
the vulnerability
um you know rating system
um but if at the end of the day it
reflects it truly if the Securities
team's priorities are truly aligned with
their vulnerability rating system then
it should be a dub for all players
yeah and like
I I'm definitely winging this take right
here which is uh I think cbss isn't the
worst place to like start and what I
mean by that is like calculate the CVSs
and then if that doesn't line up with
your security team strip model try to
figure out why and those are probably
your mitigating factors right and what I
mean by that is like okay if something's
a crit but it's actually a medium
because
blank well that's why right cpss can't
really account for that easily right
yeah maybe it's like attack complexity
hires but like it's you know it's not
right like
again like if you have an xss that can
do nothing
versus Nexus it can do an account
takeover those are two very very
different things and attack complexity
or privileges required or whatever like
those don't really account for what's
probably causing that change in severity
right and so I think being again being
transparent with the researcher
describing what has changed that has
caused it to not be a critical but to be
actually a medium or whatever
is really really important for the
program perspective and to help build
those relationships that lead to
fruitful security researcher research
from your hacker base right yeah yeah
good stuff man
um we are an hour and one minute and
I've I've had a little bit of a draining
day so that's steam that steam that was
you know coming out earlier I'm still
going it just yeah
you wrote them and yeah all right well
okay I'll just read them as I wrote them
um let me just hit you with this one big
boy uh um
regarding Bounty payments at budgets
it's not your money so why are you so
freaking stingy with it yeah okay so as
I mentioned bounties or sorry budgets
are very complex topics okay
um
I
let's see how generically I can talk
about this essentially you have to
imagine a a budget for a company as a
giant pool of money that starts from the
very very top of that company and
every single layer of management you go
down you chop another piece off okay and
so as soon as he said Giant pool of
money I just like the eyes went big like
I'm like yeah that that's what I want
it right no Justin wants the entire
let's just take the entire body I'll
take that no okay sorry go ahead
um and so the reality is that like
money is complicated and when you make a
payment like I said out of a bug Bounty
program that comes out of the bug bounty
Budget Pool which is part of the greater
security team budget which is part of
the probably engineering team budget
which is part of the yearly budget for
the entire company and when anything
starts to shift whether you go over or
under that then lots of other factors
come involved right it's like oh there's
extra money here let's take that and
spend it on a security tool or let's
um oh you don't you didn't use all that
money all right well that other team is
going to get more money because they
needed it last year and so there's like
all sorts of like weird meta aspects to
paying a bounty and to where that money
is coming from that yes it's not your
money but it kind of is your money
because it's your team's money it's you
know it's the money that you have for
next year or um it's the tooling that
you're planning to buy uh in six months
or like there are a lot of other aspects
where it kind of is your money it's it's
your money in the sense that you're you
have like ownership over it but it's not
your money right yeah
and so I think that's your Steward of
that money you're you're supposed to be
using this money for the greater purpose
of the organization that you're working
with makes sense yeah and I think very
few companies are able to keep up with
the type of pace that gets set by live
hacking event programs right
specifically
um I think it really sets an unfair bar
in terms of what people should be paying
and what's considered a reasonable
Bounty was it just blank checks
sometimes too you know to the security
team so yeah yeah I mean it's like you
know you see a program that pays
multiple millions of dollars at a single
event that is
many times the full security budget for
plenty of companies
um and like the reality is that not
everybody company can do that not every
company can keep up with that and so
that is also part of where the the
stinginess comes in which is like is
this something that we actually care
about
if I'm looking at my budget and what I'm
supposed to be paying for this is this
something that's worth paying you know
say I have fifty thousand dollars in my
budget is this worth paying 20 percent
for a 10K grit right of my whole budget
for who knows how like you know what if
it's February and you got 50k in your
budget and you just got a 10K yeah 50k
in your budget I don't know and it's
like oh okay I'm two months in and I'm I
just blew 20 of my budget like what do I
you know what happens if this happens
again in two weeks right and so I think
there's a lot of aspects where programs
start to get stingy because there are
other aspects involved around like
where's the money gonna come from and
how's the company doing in general yeah
I mean there's tons of other other
things but yeah a lot of it is just
really comes down to budgets are weird
and confusing and getting more money or
having extra money
is like a weird balance and every
company kind of handles that differently
a lot of times it's not received well
um in either case so but on the flip
side of that you know the more bounties
you pay
the more
budget you may get allocated the next
year
yeah man I uh I have a really I can
really help you out here you know like I
could I could submit you can pay him
really good and then you'll get more
money next year this is not going to be
a popular take but I think that programs
that pay a lot of money are
really just messing it all up what like
like here's the thing here's the thing
okay as a bug Bounty researcher would I
like to get lots of bounties absolutely
every day of the week
as a
program would I want to be paying
millions of dollars every single year
because my security team is not finding
those things and not fixing those things
and not detecting those things and not
securing from the inside but putting all
this emphasis in money literally just
like spending money
because we're paying other researchers
to find these things that our team
should be proactively trying to fix and
buy I don't know man I
and I know you said it's a hot take or
whatever and it is for oh for sure it's
a hot take but like but like let's say
this okay let's say you spend 500 or 500
500 000 on your support I know I'm sorry
if I have 500 000 on your
um you know on your bug Bounty reports
for this year okay
um like
let's let's say what average Bounty of
2K so you know you're resolving 250
vulnerabilities there I I you know
roughly right
um
if you were to hire a an employee let's
say a Silicon Valley engineer appsec you
know employee right let's say you're you
can hire let's be generous and let's say
we can hire two of them for 500 000
which I think I don't think you can
um what are the chances that they will
produce
125 vulnerable valid vulnerabilities
each in one year on some of the hardened
you know some some very hardened scope I
feel like that's pretty unlikely
for the math here by the way 52 weeks
five days a week is 250 days a year so
you're asking for a bug every other day
well no one's working 50 52 weeks a year
as a Silicon Valley engineer you know
just to be clear but sure but you know
they're also not they might find two
bugs in maybe 50 but yeah yeah whatever
like I think the reality is that
um the break even is pretty close
um but
if you again like I defer back to the
fact that
if you have a program that is
consistently paying insane's amounts of
bounties and that number's not going
down that means either you're raising
your bounties and finding less or you're
not doing your job
that's how I see it I like you're just
not like a security paying less bounties
right like I don't understand how your
engineering team could be outpacing
security so badly that you're paying
more money
and also I don't see how that's a good
thing it's kind of based though not
gonna lie like like you know like
at the end of the day you know from uh
from a business perspective
you you're unless you're you know
growing extremely fast and the number of
Engineers that you're employing to write
code that have mistakes in it is
increasing very fast over time security
is is a cost you know and that that cost
ideally should be going down as you
understand what mistakes your company is
making over time yeah or it goes up I
don't like it but I kind of agree with
you yeah yeah like I just don't think
that like like I see so many programs
that are like boasting like oh we paid
so much money this year yeah man that's
awesome but like
why like
what what is happening internally like
what is your security team doing okay
you need to be helping like cut this
back so much let me Devil's Advocate
that though the devil's advocate of that
is that
you're resolving
actual vulnerabilities and you're
finding out these problems every single
problem that it that is being reported
and paid for is a valid vulnerability
and that's the that's the beauty of bug
Bounty right so if you're paying out
more money it doesn't
I guess you could try to trace it all
the way back down to the cost but but at
the point you're paying it out it's
already a sunken cost you've already
have that vulnerability on your platform
and at any given point if you could pay
the money to resolve the vulnerability
that's that's the choice you're making
because of risk right
um yes but if the engineer finds it like
if your security team finds that and
fixes it and then also simultaneously
fixes 10 other bugs not only have they
saved you so much more money but also
that's what they're getting paid to do
you know like on top of paying bounties
you're paying security Engineers to run
the security team maintain the program
like do day-to-day stuff
and also you're paying bounties right
like imagine if you could take the seven
million dollars that you pay in your
bounties and
spend one and a half on salaries and
then keep six million dollars to do
whatever you like yeah I don't know like
it's just a really hard concept for me
to understand why when I see companies
bragging about the fact that they're
paying super large amount of bounties
every year I'm like yeah maybe for like
a year or two that's a good thing to see
but after that you should be paying
nowhere even close to that because your
security team should be learning from
this they should be making the changes
they should be putting stuff in place
that's gonna like oh this happened
because XYZ let's figure out how to
detect that so it doesn't happen again
yeah like this is what from a security
perspective this is what we do and when
I see companies who are like oh we paid
five million dollars last year oh before
that we paid two million I'm like what
like yeah yeah
I see it I see it I don't love it but I
see it and it sort of makes sense and I
think um that is one of the things
that's tricky about Pokemon as well is
you've got to study the bugs you're
getting
um and you really to be honest you need
at least
you know maybe maybe
um
depending on the volume of your program
but a lot of programs need a dedicated
asset a dedicated person
um to that because it is so much
research and every single time you know
you look at a bug bounding report
they're you're not seeing all of the
layers of of research that went into
getting that bug Bounty report out there
so there's a lot of reverse engineering
that needs to happen from the program
side and I was privy to
um a conversation lately thankfully
somebody came up to me and told me about
how one of my reports was dealt with
within their internal organization where
after I submitted this report
um their their internal red team is
actually you know sort of weaponizing
these these reports and they were able
to use them to accomplish uh you know a
couple tasks a couple objectives that
they had for the red team goals um uh
and that was really that was really cool
to hear and I think that's the correct
approach because that that you know that
the internal red team the internal
security team is learning from those
reports and we'll we'll make sure those
sort of mistakes don't happen again yeah
dude absolutely I like when I see
programs like not taking learnings away
which is usually pretty evident based on
how they're paying stuff and how much
they're paying it's really frustrating
because I'm like dude like
your company is like burning money like
literally just like spending money like
hand over fists to pay researchers to
pay the engineers like all this stuff
and you could save like this is an easy
justification like oh we could save a
bunch of money if we hire five new
people and have them specifically focus
on stuff that's reported by the bug
writing program to like put preventative
measures in place like
easy right like you could probably save
the bounties that you're paying you know
that you're paying you know just exactly
next question
why on Earth are you not paying me about
a triage I don't know man uh honestly
fun fact did you know this I didn't know
this uh hacker one triage is supposed to
retest bugs before their resolved
really
huh says that in the hacker one docs huh
yeah go ahead Google hacker one
retesting first result it says right
here note for response programs using
hacker one's triage Services the triage
team will retest the vulnerabilities to
verify the fixes instead of hackers
interesting
huh I'm not gonna lie from a both a
hacker and a program perspective I have
never seen that happen
wow I'm just gonna put that out there
that's that's pretty that's pretty odd
have you seen have you ever yeah I've
not I mean I've seen I've seen triagers
escalate my bugs before
um and that that mostly occurs at triage
time
um but I haven't seen them retested okay
but retesting hold on we've got a
section Joel for retesting so we'll come
to the retesting thing what I want to
know where we're at right now no no no
no no no no the question is why why are
you not issuing a bounty at triage for
oh oh triage yeah a triage not a retest
yeah oh oh okay uh I mean
yeah so okay I think that is a little
bit more pointed okay I'm gonna make it
less pointed
no no I'm Gonna Leave it I'm Gonna Leave
It point it yeah why not pay it triage
um I mean I I think you probably should
pay minimum Bounty of triage at least
um the hard part about painting at
triage is that oftentimes you don't know
what the full impact is until you can do
some further investigation sure that's
where it gets hard to pay a full Bounty
of triage
um
however like I said I think programs
should probably be trying to pay minimum
Bounty entreeage meaning you know that
this is at the very minimum X severity
medium high whatever low okay pay that
Bounty you know you're going to pay at
least that much pay some money show them
that that you appreciate the report that
it's being worked on give them some give
them some crumbs okay yeah okay okay
we've all heard we've all heard this
argument right but like why
what so I feel like there's two things
here right there's there's that
um internal technical assessment right
that will tell you exactly what the
impact of that bug is you know assuming
you do a thorough investigation and
don't miss anything right but then
there's also the triage assessment which
is just like oh no that's bad I don't
want that happening to my organization
right so like you know you you go to the
report you click on the link the alert
box pops up we can all acknowledge that
normally that's bad
right you know so so
I feel like at that point you you triage
the bug pay the lowest pay the lowest
Bounty and I mean I just wonder like do
you have any insight into why we don't
see this more often because I feel like
this is a pretty easy thing to
to do uh no I mean honestly this is one
of those things that like seems like a
no-brainer to me uh yeah I don't I have
yet to get a really good understanding
why programs don't do that okay I think
it really just boils down to the Nuance
which is that they don't want to overpay
for something accidentally because if
the minimum is so high that
it's maybe higher than a maximum for
something else sure yeah that I mean you
don't want to make that call and that's
fair but I think like you you should be
doing your best to try and pay the
minimum acceptable Bounty that you like
know for sure this is going to be at
least as much and
you know I I yeah I just think program
should be doing that well you know
that's not the answer I wanted to hear
Joel I wanted to hear I'm sorry like I
mean I cannot fathom why a program would
would be like this is worth at least as
much what we're gonna wait all right
until it's fixed I mean I don't know
that makes sense that makes sense
um like you're gonna pay them one way or
another frustrating I don't know it's
frustrating all right so let's talk
about the retesting so hacker one is
supposed to do uh apparently yeah using
hacker one retest Services hacker one is
supposed to test if you have H1 triage
yeah I mean uh
Josh says if you're using acros 300
Services the triage team is supposed to
retest the vulnerability to verify the
fix instead of hackers
now
again I in my experience in hacking both
as a researcher and as a program
operator I've never seen H1 triage do
that
not to the best of my knowledge yeah I
think they need to move that out of
those stocks everybody that I've talked
to has been like uh really that is that
is Mega workload increase for them for
sure yes yeah and like triage already
has had enough
thing but yeah I I don't I don't know
um I think
the whole like should we pay retesting
the fact that it's a feature there and
it's like literally fifty dollars just
do it yeah just pay it right like I
think if you're getting a five thousand
dollar Bounty me paying you fifty
dollars more shouldn't matter to you as
a researcher personally like I'm like
what is the what is the the
you know whatever to be honest the 50
isn't even really to be honest
the 50 isn't really that motivating in
general even like I feel like if you
want especially when programs take so
freaking long to resolve the bug like if
you resolve the bug in 24 hours and you
asked me to retest I'm gonna retest for
you because I appreciate you you know
like because that's because that's good
[__] right and and I want to encourage
that but if if it's three months down
the line I got pinged the other day to
do a retest of a bug that I reported in
January and I said uh actually I didn't
say anything because I was like I'm not
even gonna respond to that because
there's no way that I'm about to come
back to this report and and reread the
whole report and go set up the whole
thing that I need to do and we figure
out you know where that bug was and get
back in that flow state to be able to
actually test this without it I mean
that's why random people get invited to
perform retests when you don't accept it
and that's [__] by the way that is
that is absolutely not not cool that
definitely feels like a little bit of a
weird thing in terms of like my bug
being yeah and whatever but but
nonetheless
um you know I think paid retesting
should be the normal I think even if you
don't pay someone to retest doing that
retest form should be
part of the normal flow because from a
program perspective
the hacker is prompted to say whether or
not it was fixed and whether or not they
found any bypasses and that's really I
think why programs ask researchers to do
retesting in the first place is because
they don't want
to say okay this is fixed and then
tomorrow get a new report with a bypass
when the researcher
like it's not it's not really good faith
right the reality is that like
you know like if I ask you to fix
something and you'd find a bypass
and this is and this is I think is like
the program should probably be paying
like a bonus if you find a bypass I
could see like that right like the
security team should also be checking it
on their app it shouldn't just be like
oh the researcher is now going to be an
engineer and verify this on our behalf
like you should probably check it then
you should have the researcher check it
and then if the researcher finds a
bypass they should get a bonus
yeah yeah I agree I think bypasses don't
necessarily need to have 100 of the
bounty paid again unless it is
I guess unless some time has passed and
unless that Reese that that component
has changed or if the hacker had to be
in a different you know sort of Flow
State you know it's
like the way I view it from it from a
security Bridge It's Tricky but it's
this it's the same problem it's just an
incomplete fix and so asking to get paid
but it's still available for it you
can't say that you pay versus off of
impact Joel and then say that it's the
same volt and it in in you know pay for
Less
I mean it is the same vote
again it's like but it's still a vault
and it's still vulnerable and it's still
on your attacker sure this goes back to
the same conversation that we had at the
beginning of the episode you know about
zero days is like if the if the volume
is there and it's vulnerable and you're
not actively doing anything about it and
I make you do something about it then
we've completed that transaction that
bug Bounty is built upon no
sure okay but here's the thing
if it's the same problem like this is an
ongoing issue right this is not like a
new attack Vector right this is like uh
this your bug your fix is incomplete
then that doesn't deserve a new bounty
in my opinion right like if this is the
same root cause and something was
incorrectly come incorrectly fixed we're
talking about bypasses versus new
vulnerabilities here right it's not like
oh there were six months and they
regressed or maybe like a code change
that reintroduced this vulnerability
we're talking about the same
vulnerability that was not properly
fixed
and you the researcher found a bypass
I'm happy to give you a bonus for that
I'm not going to pay you the same bounty
I'm not going to pay you 2x I guess I
guess it sort of comes down to what we
Define this sort of researcher program
relationship to be because in my eyes as
us only a bug Bounty Hunter right this
is my perspective my job is to bring you
valid volts on your attack surface so
that you can fix them and make it make
it better right and secure your your
thing right
I'm not in charge of telling you how to
fix it I'm not in charge of telling you
you know
um
I'm not in charge of anything else I
just bring you the Vault right and if
you introduce a fix that it's not a
complete fix
then
I do my job again and I bring you the
vault you know and and and I I see I see
like if it's something like let's say
for example something like uh
um let's say an ssrf right and and the
the fix is like black blacklisting you
know specific hosts or whatever and you
bypass it by using like a octal encoded
IP address or something like that right
um
that that is a
scenario where
I have brought additional piece of
knowledge to the to the table and to be
just just to be clear I'm Devil's
advocating a bit here I don't mind the
bonus
um I think the bonus is is sort of is
sort of fine unless I put a substantial
amount of work into bypassing that right
and I think I think the researcher has
to be a little bit transparent about
that but
we need to be a little bit more clear I
think about what the transaction is
um in bug Bounty because at the end of
the day the the vulnerability that you
fixed as you perceived it was a
vulnerability of this ssrf can attack a
specific host you know in the scenario
and and I just brought to you that exact
same scenario again after you had
already taken that Pro that that issue
off your to-do list you're no longer
actively aware of this vulnerability and
I just brought you the exact same thing
again
yeah so
here's the thing I think a lot of teams
will view this as the same problem and I
think rightfully so because it's going
to be all the same attack Vector it's
going to be the same fixed location it's
going to be everything it's just that
the fix is different and it's not that
it's a new vulnerability it's the same
vulnerability in a different form and in
the same way that the same vulnerability
on multiple hosts
may or may not get paid as multiple
vulnerabilities
to you know they might pay a bonus
because it affects multiple things but
they probably depending on the program
probably won't be paying you that bug
times that many hosts because it's gonna
be like a single fix or it's going to be
like a one single you know usually it's
like where is the fix and and from a
program perspective
like
let me let me walk you through it
you submit a bug to me we fix it we
resolve it we pay it tomorrow you submit
the same exact vulnerability to me
except with octal encoding
that really
rubs me the wrong way okay like from
from from a program perspective like
that that is enough to like really set
things off in terms of one is this even
something valid like the program could
close that as a as a dupe of your other
report and reopen like uh
I think like not if it's already
resolved not if the report is already
released all right and so this is the
thing it's like if if their pork gets
resolved right and I think again this is
why a lot of programs will go back and
say hey can you verify the fix and let
us know if you find a bypass because if
I say hey can you verify this and you
say Yep looks fixed to me and then
tomorrow you report uh bypass to the
phone
you were lying to me like well okay okay
whoa whoa
you know okay well we do have incentive
to lie actually because we get more
money like the incentive here is that
like oh yeah that's fixed oh here's a
here's a bypass to it oh yeah that's
fixed oh here's another bypass right and
keep farming that and I I totally see
the aspect like yeah you got to make a
living however this is the same bug
right this is not like oh this is a
novel like okay but here's the thing
Joel it's not the same freaking bug
because it's it's not on your like why
do bones happen why retesting exists
this is this is why bugs have happened
in the first place is some developer
somewhere doesn't know enough and and
you know not to say that they need to
know everything you know it's okay
everyone makes mistakes it's fine but
but at the end of the day they don't
know enough about the technology they're
using to implement it properly right
that's the tldr of the situation and and
that same situation happens again when
we we have a sort of a retest to new bug
sort of situation which is we've
identified a vulnerability they've fixed
the vulnerability to the extent of their
knowledge right and then at the end and
at the end of the day that is off the
to-do list no one's thinking about it no
one's thinking like you know this is a
is a valid you know thing that we maybe
we need to go back and like you know
Workshop it no no none of that it's off
the to-do list and then the attacker
highlights that exact same sort of
problem again where it's like
you clearly aren't understanding the
technology you're working with here to
the extent that you need to to protect
your users right and and I don't know it
just feels like you know what
I I think we're going around in circles
here I understand where this is going to
go
um yeah I actually I mean I have sort of
talked myself into a little bit of a
different position than I had at the
beginning of this argument I think which
is that
if our job is not actually to advise you
on how to fix this vulnerability and
sometimes it is and sometimes it isn't
right then I think retests needs to be
new new either more strongly compensated
than the 50 bucks that that hacker one
offers or they need to be new bucks yeah
like again I think that the program
should be fairly compensating right and
if that means like if you find a unique
like a novel bypass like I should be at
least giving you that 50 for the retest
right like yeah the reality is that like
as I mentioned this should not be like
you should not be the security team
right the security team should be
verifying this themselves in some cases
h13i should also be verifying this
themselves like there should be other
layers of verification in place before
this gets the researcher not only does
it make the security team look bad if
the researcher finds a bypass so they're
fixed but it also means that you didn't
do your job well and so like I think if
it gets that far like there should be at
least some sort of compensation for the
time and the effort
but I don't see it as a totally unique
new vulnerability that deserves a
freshman payout here's an interesting
thing is that
as an as a hacker you can
like say with the ssrf scenario right
let's say I I put in a new host you know
you you hit that host okay that whole
thing goes to the thing and I know in
the beginning you know what I bet this
uses octal encoding too and I bet
because there's already a white list
they're just gonna fix the white list
right or whatever right
um or the I'm sorry The Blacklist
um
and then you withhold that information
from the original report right that
that's that is that is tricky that is
dishonest and not something that I would
do right but I also feel like there's a
flip side of this which is that programs
also have this sort of trickiness when
it comes to impact assessment because
you can look at your organization and
say okay wow this guy found an exercise
on this one host that actually affects
1500 hosts right and then pay them out
for the specific you know the the one
bug right
um because they didn't know right so
there are there are things that that
both parties yeah can bring to the table
that that will portray honesty that will
um maintain their you know ethical
Integrity in this in this exchange and
um and I think that's a valuable part of
building that program researcher
relationship I think there's also the
case with retesting where in a retest I
will do a retest if I'm interested in
building a good relationship with the
program
um and they've sort of you know paid
that same respect forward right
um and so I think I think it can be a
tool just like anything else to build
build the relationships that bug Bounty
is really built upon yeah and I I think
like that point you made is like I think
it's a kind of a good way to think about
it it's like okay if if I have two
different ways to exploit this octal and
normal encoding for example if I submit
them both at the same time
almost certainly one would be duped on
the other one absolutely if I report one
wait for it to be fixed and Report the
other one
probably the same thing should happen to
some extent now if I report them both in
the same report does that mean I should
get extra money
um
maybe maybe not
I think when it comes specifically down
to bypassing a fix that's when extra
money should start to come into play
where it's we we fix this no you didn't
right like if I was a different
researcher this would be a new report
right
and that I think is where it gets to be
fair where you can start to throw extra
money in there
but simply as like
if you know that like these two things
are both possible and then only one of
them gets fixed I think you are somewhat
obligated to tell them like hey by the
way
you know and I think the program in good
faith should
pay for that yeah to some extent
yeah it's an interesting conversation
man I I think uh unexpectedly got a
little a little bit you know like that
actually got a little bit tricky uh yeah
for sure he did there and um yeah I
think I think uh I think
there's definitely a lot of Ethics that
comes into bug Bounty that's under
talked about we should do an episode on
that and I think uh I think I want to
say it was Joe Bob sir
um yeah I think it was jubobs that
commented on the the Twitter post we
were talking about topics that that
would be a good topic I totally agree
we'll have to we'll have to think about
that
um okay so we are we are at like what an
hour 30. you doing okay you got a couple
more minutes yeah
um let me see which one of these are
gonna hit the hardest because we're not
gonna hit all these
um
I I guess we sort of talked about this
sort of systemic issue piece when we
when we talked about you know in this
last conversation as well
um
from a program perspective
from your experiences do you think it's
it is dishonest
to withhold specific reports for any
given period of time
depends on the severity
um
if it's
a crit
yeah probably unethical
um
like I I think
it depends on two two things well I mean
one thing really like severity which
should be based on impact
like the reality is that the reason that
a bug bending program exists and the
reason that you participate in a bug
bending program is to try and increase
the security of that company in a
ethical and
profitable way for the researcher and
for the company right they're saving
money yeah they're you know whatever
if you start to hold stuff
the
I mean there's a lot of
tangential stuff you can get into right
like why are you holding it is it for a
live hacking event is it because
or whatever right like don't add me bro
what are you doing it depends I know a
lot of researchers myself included will
hold bugs like uh you know for like a
week or two you know depending right the
programs know this just to be clear you
know we're not they know this yeah yeah
like you know the thing is that like
researchers start hacking before the
submission window gets open and they
might have stuff stocked up that they're
ready to submit because they want to
submit it through the special event
program or whatever like or they want to
use it for like a later bug chain or
something yeah I think the ethics
of that are really complicated
um from a program perspective I
obviously we want to hear about
everything but the reality is that not
everything needs to be heard and
reported like if it's an open redirect
that is something that's a lot easier to
make that decision for you know what I
mean like if it's something that's like
uh mostly a non-issue unless it's used
in another circumstance and chained
together with something then I think
that's that's fine like I understand
that like
you know
that may not be the best case however I
think it's still something that the
company should eventually hear about
um like if it's like an eye door that or
like an endpoint that leaks a lot of IDs
that you can then use for an eye door
the company should probably hear about
that to some like interesting that's
interesting either through your report
or either uh through if you chain it
like you know put them both in your
report and then reference that report in
future reports like if you have another
idor that uses that same type of ID be
like as I showed in
I I think that there are ways that you
can disclose stuff without losing your
bug you know what I mean like you can
prove that these things exist and these
things are possible and that makes it a
lot easier to make an impact case for
your book yeah the same way that like
if you have one bug that shows that
cookies are scoped to every sub domain
on on a root domain right right later
you find another xss on the subdomain of
the roof domain
you can use that as a case you I mean
you should use that and say as you know
look this happens there are cookies like
sensitive cookies that have been
previously scoped two main domains and
you know it's a plausible scenario that
it could happen yeah I feel like that
kind of goes against the POC or GTFO
piece of bug Bounty though you know like
I mean I guess you can say that yeah
from one you know from one or you know
actually I mean like don't get upset if
the program says okay yes but it's not
exploitable right now that's a good
point it's like you know if if you if
you do report it and they close it as an
informative you know I I don't think
they should close it informative I think
that they should that should be a
mitigating Factor but I think it should
absolutely be something that's relevant
to like okay yeah this was that like six
months ago this would have been
exploitable right yeah it's a separate
bug then whatever like
I I think that's that's reasonable like
when we look at impact internally a lot
of times we'll ask was this ever
possible like was was there ever a case
where cookies could be scoped to the
subdomain accidentally or globally and
then you could get an ATO with an excess
like you know if that's something that's
happened and it is possible within the
bounds of the infrastructure that's
being used then that's something that
should be taken as a serious
consideration as a possibility of
something that could happen or exist
somewhere else right like the fact that
that pattern ever was there means that
that pattern can be there again okay so
I think like that's that's something
that should be kept in mind so again
like don't get a mess like don't don't
get all frustrated if the program's like
okay well yes but this isn't actively
exploitable right now so we're gonna put
a mitigating Factor on that so so what
you're describing here is I guess the
most communicative or most respectful
way to interact with the program in that
regard which is like let's say we've got
the idore ID generator right you report
that to them they don't accept it as a
bug we're not upset about that but they
know that that exists right and and
they're able to use that in their impact
assessments and then next time we find
about where we actually utilize this
then we
reference it and say Here's the you know
that's the that's the report yeah I mean
and again like personally like as a
researcher I probably wouldn't just
report that by itself unless it was 100
if it's just IDs like
um like again very low security impact
here but if I had another eye door
I might report those two things together
and then again if I find a third idor
later down the line references right
then I could say hey okay you know as I
showed in this other report it's
possible to leak these IDs like maybe I
had them all stored as an attacker or I
web archived them or uh whatever like I
I don't really think you have to get
that in depth about like yeah like this
this is how an attacker could have
gotten it it's like I showed that it was
possible to get them right okay so yes
that that makes sense I'm gonna jump
into the timeline section here because
I've actually got a couple pointed
questions that I'd like to ask and and
get your response on yeah
the the first one that I'm just gonna
drop is like
I'm curious what an actual root cause
analysis looks like from a program's
perspective and an impact assessment
like and why the heck does it take so
damn long sometimes like like I know
there's a lot of code right but if you
dropped me into a production code base
with grep you know like and and I and I
have a unique parameter name or whatever
I would expect to be able to find the
code that is responsible for this thing
within an hour max like am I crazy like
you know that's totally doable but what
does that give you that gives me the
yeah I know where it happens yeah but
like does that tell me what it can do
does that give me the impact of what it
what is capable from there that's where
it takes more nuanced understanding so
finding where it actually exists like
where the actual root cause is that is
generally pretty easily it's the easy
part yeah it generally depends on the
org like some Orcs are a lot more
organized than others uh I'd say that
where I work it's very straightforward
it's pretty you know
yeah very easy to like see oh okay this
endpoint points to the service which is
handled here just line of code right
like easy
um other companies probably not as easy
it depends on the company depends on how
like well structured they are but
the hard part is like okay like what
could you do with this and that's where
it takes Knowledge from like a security
engineer or somebody to or maybe just
even a normal engineer who understands
what the rest of the infrastructure
looks like what can that service talk to
uh what access what data access does it
have so for each bug a store having a
meeting with the with these Engineers
are you sending an email is it a message
I mean yeah I mean it's like a usually
it's a message so like
typically here's what happens with the
report and and this is again generic
this is not like sure specific to either
program but like just rough I'd say like
most of the time
report comes in gets validated by either
the team or triage or some it gets
triaged somehow right in one way or
another then that ticket that report
gets turned into an internal ticket
which gets assigned to an engineer
sometimes with a root cause sometimes
with a fix usually one or both
and then from there it's up to the
engineer and their team to fix it and
that priority is generally up to the
engineering team not up to the security
team sometimes it's up to the security
team sometimes there are agreements that
say like you know security tickets have
this SLA they need to be fixing this
amount of time
um you know there's this much priority
if it doesn't get prioritized then we'll
have discussions with leadership or
whatever right it's crazy to me that
like you guys have such segments in
these big organizations where it's like
all right like when I hear SLA I think
like external vendor agrees to do XYZ by
you know external time but you're
literally talking to somebody in your
own company and saying yeah okay we have
an SLA agreement where you got to fix
this you know by this time yeah it's
really that's and what you have to
realize is that like the engineering
team is not just like sitting around
waiting for the security team to be like
hey we got something for you to think
yeah right like every single day while
the security team is handling other bugs
and all that kind of stuff the engine
engineering team is being told by the
product team oh like here's a new
feature we want you to write and can you
implement this and can you fix this bug
in like non-security bugs security is
not their thing logical bug right like
can you add this feature can you
whatever like all these other things
that relate to like their day-to-day
engineering job and then a new thing
comes into that system and is like hey
make room for me yeah and it doesn't
even and I'm sure these devs are aligned
with the vision you know sometimes two
of the products iteration you know of
the products development and this can
kind of seem I bet 99 of the time this
feels like a blocker and this feels like
just this annoying little task they got
to get out of the way yeah to move on
with their actual features that they're
developing yeah and so I think this is
where like a lot of nuance Falls in
between like the relationship between
security teams and Engineering teams and
how to like promote security as like a
core value because it's it can be very
difficult to get Engineers to give a
[__] about security issues because it's
exactly what you're describing which is
that like there's a new ticket that's
just like popped up out of nowhere that
is now increasing their workload and is
now a thing that they have to take care
of right onto my kanban board or
whatever and it's like not they weren't
planning on this right this wasn't
something that was on the radar it
wasn't in their Sprint it wasn't in
their planned amount of work and now
they have this extra thing that they
have to deal with and that goes all the
way up the chain it goes to the man
their manager goes to the product like
everybody now has to account for this
extra load within the system and it
really depends like on how the team's
view security as like it should be like
a helpful thing right like this is to
like stop like prevent issues everybody
should be owning security and so like
there's a lot of nuanced aspects to
getting the engineering teams and not
just engineering but all the teams to
take security seriously and own it
um and that can be difficult and if you
have a team who get who gives a [__]
about security and like they respect it
and when a security issue comes in they
take it seriously that's the best type
of relationship that's typically where
you see stuff get fixed very fast like
yeah responsive all that kind of stuff
man but if it doesn't you just have to
realize that like you you and your issue
are battling are battling against
uh so many other things you're batting
against the product team who tells that
engineering team what to do you're
battling against the sea levels and the
management teams who are trying to drive
the business in a certain direction like
there are so many other things that the
security team as much as they'd like to
have number one priority and be the most
important thing just can't I wonder I
wonder how
we as bug bounty hunters or we even as
external Consultants to an organization
could help
Foster that sort of relationship with
the devs like I I guess I'm sure that's
a that's a challenge and one of the
challenges that I've not been exposed to
as I'm not a you know ciso or even you
know an abstract engineer but but that
seems like a good investment of time
it's like having your security Champions
or whatever in your various um deaf
product teams and stuff like that that
are really like you've invested in
somehow making them
um appreciate security and and you know
Champion it within their little little
block their little team
yeah absolutely I like there are various
ways you can do that I think one really
great way for bug Bounty especially is
any valid bug Bounty report is an
external vulnerability report right
somebody outside the company found it
it's a valid vulnerability and it
affects your company with no special
permissions it affects it externally
right that's a huge yeah like
thing that you can use to Advocate and
say like an external security researcher
found this volume on our site and is
currently actively exposed externally
we need to fix that that's a big deal
let's fix again right yeah that's a big
deal and I think that you can at least
use that to help Drive
the importance of it and then you can
use that again as backup when you're
like training your engineers so like one
of the things that we'll do internally
is we'll take a lot of these things that
we notice like systemic problems or like
core problems that are popping up over
and over again and we'll try and turn
that into trainings that then every
single new hire engineer gets put
through this security training that
walks them through like how the security
process should work yeah but it's
training you know like but this is like
day one okay yeah but like trust me it
works I I promise we wouldn't do it if
it didn't work okay it really it helps a
lot it helps people understand that like
security matters and is taken seriously
it shows them from day one that security
is not just like a background process
but it is part of the process yeah and
that when they when they want to like
expose a new endpoint security has to
know and security has to review that and
like that is like a real core part of
the Engineering Process and it it states
it as a fact instead of an option that
that that is important and I'm sure that
that's and intentional cultural thing
you've got to Foster and you know my
next question here on the list is like
why the frick does it take so long like
aren't you guys using agile like like
can't you just like just slip it into
the next Sprint and it be fixed in the
week you know if I were up to be
absolutely yes but again
yeah yep yep it's a company culture
problem it's a it's a you're fighting
with all these other teams and all these
other organizations and all these other
tickets and all these other everything
like again if it was just security and
three Engineers I'm sure the
relationship would be such that like
we'd be like hey can you fix this and
they'd be like sure and then they'd fix
it but there are so many other
players that are invisible to the
researcher and so many other like you
know just communication and
organizational type problems that are
really hard to get around that even if
the security team
knows in their heart that this is an
important thing it doesn't always
get
received that same way by the
engineering team and so the best thing
that you can do is work in the
background to try and make security more
valuable and have more weight to it when
they say hey we have a vulnerability
like figure out how the engine how to
get the engineering team to understand
that
oh this is an external vulnerability
when the security team comes to me with
something that that's I need to fix this
this is important for the company it's
important for our users it's important
for our data whatever yeah I just I have
a hard time like and maybe it doesn't
come across to the devs this way but I
have a hard time
like reconciling that they have two
tickets one is like change the CSS
styling on this button and the other one
is like present prevent Mass data
leakage of all your users right you know
and like some happy brain bro somehow do
I I mean is it is that is that really
how it is sorry listen like no like as a
security person of course like security
is number one for me I like absolutely
security should be number one it should
be the number one priority it should
take precedent over everything what
it's not my decision we don't we don't
have to debate that that's fine okay
um a couple of last couple questions
um
do you ever reread dupe informative
reports that have been set that way by
hacker one triagers or is that just like
a
is that like something that would
ideally happen but like just very rarely
happens when you actually you know do
something with it
so I try to yes I try to read through
like I try to watch everything that
they're doing I'm not gonna lie yeah I
hope that this doesn't portray H1 triage
in a negative or unfavorable light uh
the reality is that they have a very
difficult job and that very difficult
job is trying to manage and validate
reports across thousands of companies
hundreds to thousands of companies I
don't know how how many programs each
triage is responsible for but I know
that I see a lot of the same names
across a lot of a lot of different
programs right so so the reality is that
they're dealing with a lot of different
things and they're trying to do that at
scale
um like many many times a day and that
is a difficult job to do
it's a difficult job to do it well and
it's difficult job to do it to this
standard that and like somebody who
works for that company would be like oh
that's how I would do it right and
everybody's standard is different this
is why external triage Services exist
like once not provided by the platform
but
like a cohort of people who you pay sure
NCC group right to do your triage for
you and those that type of stuff that
that's because it's much more nuanced
it's like oh I want you to like handle
this in a certain way and I want you to
like do this these specific things like
You're gonna pay extra for that you're
not gonna oh yeah when you when you pay
for H1 triage you're not paying for
three specific people to just be like
your triagers maybe if you're paying the
millions of dollars a year you'll get
that most programs are not gonna be
getting right okay like the reality is
that like 99 of programs are not gonna
be getting that level of triage
experience sure it's like oh this is my
triage team who handles things in this
specific way and I get to tell them what
to do in your experience do the same H1
triagers work with your program on a
regular basis or is that you know uh
it's like the same handful of them sure
I'd be lying if I said that there
weren't specific instances where we've
like had one thing with like a specific
triager and had something had to be
reassigned but like sure often from what
I can tell it's Who's online in this
time zone and like who who you know
who's online who who's triaging right
now yeah sometimes it's the same people
sometimes it's not I think not every
triager has access to every program so
there is going to be some cohort that is
responsible for your program but it's
going to vary by time zone and like what
time the report comes in and whatever
um so yeah because of all that because
there's so much like they have to do so
many things they like nobody's gonna be
perfect and so
for my programs I'm going to look and
I'm going to see like did they mess
anything up I'm not going to do that 100
of the time because I want to trust them
and yeah like there's that's just way
too much overhead there's no point
paying for triage right you're just
gonna do it yourself right um
but but if you see something most of the
time they're pretty good if you see
something that looks weird that's
getting closed by a trio Usher what do
you say okay let me let me let me put
this a little bit differently
um
in the experiences you've had dealing
you know talking to other program
managers in your own programs in your
friends that are managing programs
what do you think the chances are that a
if a valid bug was closed by hacker one
triage what do you think the chance is
that the program will catch it
I'm not going to put a number on it
because I don't I don't want to
um yeah but I'd say it's pretty good
that it would get caught it it really
depends that was not the answer I was
expecting to be honest when I wrote this
question like if something gets closed
like it really depends on the program
and it's gonna depend on like yeah who's
managing it and how much attention
they're paying to it and how much of a
[__] they give yeah um yeah the reality
is that like as I said a lot of programs
will be like why are we paying for H1
triage if we're gonna look through this
ourselves right that's valid like why
are you paying for h13 if you're gonna
go look through it yourself right but I
think it's also your responsibility as a
program manager to if you see something
that isn't in line with the standard
spam reports you're getting and anybody
who manages the program kind of knows
what I'm saying which is basically that
like every program has a certain cohort
of things that are very common like
clearly just something you're gonna get
spammed on all the time sure not
something that we care about or this is
like not even a security issue or
whatever
um and the reality is that like
when you see stuff outside of that it's
very obvious
um and so even if it is like
uh uh like gets immediately marked as
like informative or duplicate you're
probably gonna look at it because you'll
be like huh that's something different
like that's not just what I'm normally
used to seeing now I think if you get a
lot of submissions that can be harder to
identify and I think the more
submissions that you get the harder you
start to lean on trees program versus
private program that sort of thing yeah
like the harder you're going to lead on
triage to basically like be that helping
hand to First filter stuff out like the
whole reason that triage exists is oh we
don't have to look at a report in a new
state we look at a report in a triage
state like I don't have to say oh this
is valid this isn't valid uh this is
valid because XYZ like triage should be
like okay you're getting a bug because
we reproduced it and it's valid and you
can turn that into a ticket yeah right
um yeah well that's that's uh that's
reassuring you know to hear the fact
that that there's a decent chance that
if something was slipping through the
crack and and like you said it depends
on the programs for sure but if you're
submitting a valid bug to to a program
that is not
like just getting slaughtered with
reports all the time there's a pretty
decent chance that it it'll get caught
even if it gets miscategorized yeah but
this totally depends on like who's
running it yeah like how how much
attention are they paying yeah
um
internal activity on a report what does
that mean what what why am I not seeing
this like what like it's really funny to
see this as a question because like like
this is totally normal stuff from like a
program management okay so basically
when you leave a comment on a report
there's like you leave a comment that's
it you know you just like type something
up you just press post and it goes into
your your Parker board well you probably
don't realize is that there's like
hidden internal Communications that
happen also on your report that you
don't see so yeah like when a ticket uh
for example if you link it to an
internal ticket that is internal
activity we can type out comments that
are only seen by the triage team and it
has like a red background like you don't
it's you know Market but like it's a
hidden okay so is internal activity a
good indicator that the report is
actually being worked on or is there
like this ticket hasn't been updated in
23 days sort of notifications that go on
that definitely figures that something's
happening like if there's internal
Communications that means that
the triage team and the internal team
are having discussions on your ticket
privately interesting and they want that
to be tied to the ticket
well why don't you just do it in front
of me so I can see what's going on
because oftentimes it's not relevant for
the researcher to know these things or
it'll be like
for example
triage will say oh we're having trouble
validating this
internal team can you help sure and the
internal team will be like oh uh you
know he uh you know XYZ like we'll give
you no
no like yeah do your job
that's what it is it's like you and the
it's it's the internal teams teams uh
whether that's you know the people
running the program or the triage team
or whatever having Communications
talking trying to figure out you know if
something is stuck that usually means
that there's like something weird going
on gotcha but internal activity is real
is real okay yeah
that is uh that is and I'm sure you know
there are caveats to that like I'm sure
some programs have like internal
automation or whatever that will comment
on the ticket you know and say like this
ticket hasn't been bloody blonde bloody
blah but whatever but most of the time
that's gonna be actual activity yeah
it's a good sign that like people are
alive and doing this okay yeah that's
good no need to ask for a follow-up then
if I see internal activity you know
happening
um yeah
all right so two two two questions
um one you can one you can opt to opt
out of the other one you cannot opt out
I already know which one I'm up to God
are you are you opting out of it how
much does it cost to run a bug Bounty
program Joel like come on you got to
tell me something about that
I definitely can't tell you hard numbers
on anything however what I can tell you
is that there are different payment
models depending on each company I
definitely almost definitely cannot tell
you like what the per program I'll tell
you off air how about that okay all
right yeah yeah maybe I'll tell you off
here
um it is definitely tens of thousands of
dollars a year okay minimum and that's
Inc and then you also have like Bounty
Budget on top of that right so there's a
fee for the program itself there's a fee
for triage Services there's a if you
decide to do that there's a fee for that
that's like dollar for dollar or more
for when you pay bounties right so if I
pay a five thousand dollar bounty to you
that comes out of my bounty pool which
is separate from the amount of money
that I'm paying hacker one or forever
that makes sense just to run my program
right so I pay a yearly contract to
platform for whatever maybe triage the
program itself Etc and then in addition
to that there's a separate amount of
money that all the bounties come out of
and if that amount runs low then you
make another deposit sure okay gotcha so
there's and then whenever you pay a
bounty
um you can potentially
you know platform also takes some of the
top off that or you know some amount of
that also gets paid to the platform
inside that's where it varies
um I believe the newer Contracting
models they don't
they don't do that they don't do fees
like that anymore they used to do a flat
20 fee
um which I think is public
um but since then lots of stuff has
changed it really depends on like
usually when you renew contract you
might negotiate that with the platforms
sure to determine like how you want to
do your fee structure should you pay
fees ahead of time like all that kind of
stuff so yeah that that varies a lot
solid
um last question this has been a
absolute freaking marathon of an episode
I have not even done that much talking
and I am exhausted I can't imagine how
you must feel but talk to me about lhes
are they with live hacking events for
those of you that aren't familiar with
acronym
how does that feel from the program side
is that stressful is that fun is that
all of the above
yeah all the above all the above um I
run a couple live hacking events
um while I was at Uber
they are
uh they don't call it a war room for
nothing okay
like uh yeah it's um it's it's chaos in
there I'm not gonna lie okay so
basically here's the picture all right
you've got at least a couple people from
the security team in there you've
probably got at least a couple people
from the engineering team or people on
call remotely who can help answer
questions and not like direct tickets in
the right direction and then you've got
the triage team and the H1 team in there
as well so triage is helping like
validate stuff in real time like login
test stuff like if they need something
from the security team for help
retesting or whatever they're there
security team is there to like look at
all the bugs address criticality address
impact address validity
um see if this is stuff that needs to be
fixed like now now or can wait until
after the event
[Music]
um
figuring out payouts that's like a huge
part of it is like the security team
meeting trying to decide impact on like
10 bugs every hour or more that's like a
weekly meeting that happens but actually
every hour it's like you're sitting down
you're like okay what about this one oh
what could they do uh they could do this
this okay uh well that's you know the
severity blah blah okay let's pay it out
this next yeah that's intense man and
you're making you're making big money
decisions on the fly like that that's
nuts yes yeah so definitely
um stressful definitely a lot of fun I
think like in hindsight it's such a
great experience to get to have that
real like face-to-face interaction with
the researcher and those relationships
um there's so much
like partnership building that you can
do in just like that one day of hacking
between like top hackers and your
program that like build like lifelong
like sorts of relationships where those
hackers now want to come hack on your
program they have a face that they
assign when they submit a report yeah
and they have like a real you know
there's a real tie there super valuable
it it adds a lot um yes they're
stressful yes they're expensive yes it's
chaos but uh is it worth it yeah I I
would certainly say so I think it
depends on the company not every company
can run a live hacking event
um there are certainly tons of companies
who should not run oh I'm happy that oh
yeah for sure yeah like you don't have
the scope for it you don't have the
Bounty for it uh you don't have the team
for it you don't have like yeah that
like I think I was telling it to the
hack on my team I I feel like honestly
one of the requirements for running a
live hacking event should be that one of
your people at least has to come on site
and just sit in the war room and watch
what a live hacking event looks like of
somebody else's live hacking event uh
just be like oh [__] okay this is what
we get this is gonna rock my world yeah
like I I feel like they need some
perspective because so many companies
will come in and be like we want to run
a live hacking event and I I think
I mean if I worked at a hacker one my
reaction would be huh what you do yeah
really are you sure are you sure yeah
like we'll take your money but are you
sure that's a pretty interesting yeah
like like live hacking event training or
something like that could be exactly so
much like you want it to be a good
experience for the researchers you want
it to be a good experience for the
company you want it to be a good
experience like overall you want like
good Bounty payouts you want everybody
to walk away Happy Swag like all these
things there's so many movie parts so
many aspects that like there's a reason
why you see a lot of the same companies
running live hacking events over and
over again because they have the money
they have the scope they have the
everything yeah the Stars really gotta
align for it it had to happen
wow dude
all right Joel that was a marathon of an
episode I think this is the longest
episode we've ever done
um we definitely went down some rabbit
holes we definitely you know went off on
each other a little bit there
um I I think overall you you did a great
job answering all these questions and uh
I'm gonna go take a nap now uh but for
the for those for those few of you that
are still with us at the end of this
episode
um one you rock
to
um uh
check out the new website check out the
newsletter that's there go ahead and
subscribe to those and uh also we have a
kaido referral code which we've
mentioned on Twitter but we haven't
really you know
um made Mega public in an episode before
um we'll probably announce it at the
beginning of next week's episode as well
um but for those of you that are still
with us uh you can go ahead and use that
and get uh 10 off of your kaido
subscription
um which we would appreciate and you
would also appreciate because that saves
you money
um do you know what that code is off the
top of your head oh yes that's a good
that's a good point I should I should
actually say what it is it's a ctbb
podcast it's our handle on Twitter
um critical thinking bug Bounty podcast
um and that will that will get you uh 10
off on your kind of subscription
um that's kind of c-a-i-d-o yes every
time we mention it on the Pod everyone's
like what's the time
what's a kiado you know like no
um
so all right Joel you got anything
before I fall asleep go take a nap from
exhaustion because that that is that's
it I'm glad I've been chugging Kevin
this whole time you've been chugging man
yeah you were you're like I you know
towards the end you can kind of see me
like you know lower the desk and then
yeah like start like slumping like
but it doesn't help either because I had
like a two-hour meeting this morning and
then and then my my buddy came over and
we just chatted for a little while so
like two hours and you know like I'm not
really I'm not an extrovert I'm an
introvert so this sort of you know
long-form talking takes a toll on me you
know and so I'm at like minimum energy
right now but we made it we made it
through the episode so yeah dude well
yeah thanks for um thanks for having
this discussion I hope that I helped to
answer some of the Mysteries behind you
did anybody and reports and what what
the hell's going on with my ticket and
all that kind of stuff and um yeah if we
if there's more questions that come
after this we can certainly do for sure
follow-up episode or something all right
GG man that's pod
that's fun
foreign
[Music]